

I am a polymath, empathetic, proactive and pragmatic individual. I am skillful with teamwork, however I usually opt for a wide degree of autonomy and time flexibility. I like challenges and I seek them actively. I am currently involved in research, showing special prowess at mathematical modeling and computer programming tasks. Furthermore, as a competent and active social volunteer, I have direct experience interacting with vulnerable population and designing and implementing social development and educational projects at local scale. I am confident carrying out complex quantitative or qualitative analyses, specially in fields such as applied micro- or macroeconomics, and public policy.

ACADEMIC INTERESTS

Public Policy
Social Networks
Behavioral Economics
Algorithmic Statistics
Computer Science
Political Economy
Community Socioeconomics
Philosophy of Economics

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Kampagne für Frieden in Kolumbien sos-colombia.de

Cordillera EV cordillera.eu

Nicolas E. Fajardo-Acosta

EDUCATION

Economics (M.Sc.)

2019 – 2021 Diss. "Scaling Up Preschool Education: A Semiparametric

Estimation of its Effect on Early Learning Outcomes in Peru"

Diss. supv. Prof. Lena Janys Faculty of Law and Economics

Bonn, DEU RHEINISCHE FRIEDRICH-WILHELMS-UNIVERSITÄT BONN

 ${\it Advanced modules} \qquad {\it Computational Statistics, Public Economics, Labor Economics, Growth and Development}$

Economics, Banking and Securitization, Behavioral Public Policy. Research emphasis in

Applied Microeconomics.

Economics (B.Sc.)

2014 – 2019 Faculty of Economic Sciences [FCE]

Bogotá, col UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA

Advanced modules Post-Keynesian Macroeconomics. History of Biological Thought. Critical Perspectives on

Economic Theory. Dynamic Programming. Computational Economics. Project Design, Management and Evaluation. Economics and Politics of Sustainability. Behavioral Economics. Finance, Crises and Inequality. Microeconometrics. Advanced Growth Economics.

Economic Theory and Policy, Design Thinking, Epistemology of Psychology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Short-Term Consultant

10/2021-03/2022 Trade and Integration Unit

Supvs. Drs. Isabela Manelici, José P. Vásquez and Román D. Zárate

Development Economics Vice Presidency

Remote WORLD BANK GROUP

Duties Develop algorithms to match highly irregular databases, using a mix of manual matching

and regular-expression rules. Support the research process in all its stages.

Research Assistant

11/2019-01/2022 Worked for Drs. Stephanie Majerowicz, Román A. Zárate, Franz

Ostrizek, Armin Falk among others.

Bonn, DEU BEHAVIOR AND INEQUALITY RESEARCH INSTITUTE [BRIQ]

Duties Clean and manage large databases, ranging between 1 and 25 million observations.

Implement and execute multiple estimators of treatment effects using Machine Learning and parallelized algorithms. Complete plots and proofs using Wolfram Mathematica. Review relevant literature on Economics of Education, Social Networks and Moral Action.

Investments Analyst

01/2019 – 08/2019 Front Office

Supv. Andrés Enrique Rodríguez Arévalo

Investments Department

Bogotá, COL SOCIEDAD FIDUCIARIA DE DESARROLLO AGROPECUARIO S.A.

Duties Analyze the economic behavior of local and international markets. Design strategies and

valuate fixed-income investment portfolios. Develop econometric models for forecasting. Write and present briefing papers and reports, including Daily Market Dashboards. Lead biweekly internal meetings on current macro-financial developments. Communicate

 $with\ clients,\ market\ analysts\ and\ traders.$

Intern

01/2018 – 12/2018 Economic Policy Studies Department

Supv. Norberto Rodríguez Niño

Office of the Deputy Technical Governor

Bogotá, COL BANCO DE LA REPÚBLICA DE COLOMBIA

Duties Gather, clean, reshape and analyze databases. Implement structural and semi-structural econometric models, such as State-Space representations, VAR and VAR-X. Execute panel

data estimators. Develop algorithms for mathematical optimization, web scraping and text mining. Estimate bayesian DSGE models. Review relevant literature on analysis and

evaluation of Monetary Policy.

Nicolas Fajardo

SKILLS

PERSONAL

Resolute, reasonable, social, empathetic, innovative, agile, insightful, autonomous.

COMMUNICATIVE

Spanish C2
English C1
German B2/C1
French A1

PROGRAMMING

R, Python, Matlab (Octave), Maxima (Mathematica), Stata, ŁTĘX, OTree, Dynare, SAS, PostgresQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Microsoft Office.

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Social intervention Communal work Music [Violin & Guitar] Performing arts Aerial silk

Poetry and creative writing

Graphic design

Ecological conservation

Permaculture

ACADEMIC REFERENCES

Prof. Dr. Phillip Eisenhauer Universität Bonn peisenha@uni-bonn.de

Prof. Lena Janys Universität Bonn ljanys@uni-bonn.de

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Asst. Prof. Isabela Manelici London School of Economics i.manelici@lse.ac.uk

Asst. Prof. Román A. Zárate University of Toronto ra.zarate@utoronto.ca

Asst. Prof. Stephanie Majerowicz Universidad de los Andes s.majerowicz@uniandes.edu.co

Markus Antony Scientific Manager briq Institute markus.antony@briq-institute.org

COURSES AND SEMINARS

Participant

01/2020 Basic course on Human Research

Social & Behavioral Research Investigators Massachusetts Institute of Technology Affiliates

Online COLLABORATIVE INSTITUTIONAL TRAINING INITIATIVE [CITI]

Participant

08/2019 • Micro Data for Economic Policy and Development

o6/2016 – 07/2016 • From Nudge to regulating Uber

Homero Cuevas Seminar

Faculty of Economic Sciences [FCE]

Bogotá, COL UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA

Participant

02/2019 – 03/2019 · Territorial Actions on Peace-building

03/2019 – 04/2019 · Participatory Policy-making

District Institute for Participation and Communal Action

Online ALCALDÍA MAYOR DE BOGOTÁ D.C.

in cooperation with

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL ABIERTA Y A DISTANCIA

Participant

08/2018 - 09/2018 3th Certificate Course on Informal Settlements:

Impact, Participation & Community development

Bogotá, col FUNDACIÓN TECHO - COLOMBIA

Speaker

10/2017 "Social innovation & Microcredit:

¿Are we financing the status quo of poverty?" VIII International Public Policy Colloquium: Public Policy Implementation and Peace-building

Bogotá, COL UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA

Participant

01/2017 • International Financial Markets

01/2017 • Financial Mathematics

Unit of Analysis on Economic Sciences [UACE]

Bogotá, COL UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA

PUBLICATIONS

Working papers

02/2019 "Inflows of International Tourists to Colombia during 2001-2017:

Evolution, Characteristics and Determinants"

(with C. Agudelo, C. González, E. Montes & N. Rodriguez) BORRADORES DE ECONOMÍA: BANCO DE LA REPÚBLICA Nº 1064

Manuscripts

08/2017 "Social innovation & Microcredit:

¿Are we financing the status quo of poverty?" (with S. Espinosa-Moyano & D. Gantiva-Parada) ECONOGRAFOS: ESCUELA DE ECONOMÍA FCE - CID Nº 113

Nicolas Fajardo

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Scholarship holder

10/2019 - 09/2021 Scholarship Program for Foreign Students

Bonn, DEU KONRAD-ADENAUER STIFTUNG

Top 10 pct. Graded Average: Economics

08/2019 Undergraduate Degree Earners in 2019-01

Faculty of Economic Sciences [FCE]

Bogotá, COL UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE COLOMBIA

Best score: at National level

12/2018 Reference group: *Economics*

SABER-PRO 2017 "La Noche de los Mejores" Test on the Quality of Higher Education

Bogotá, COL MINISTERIO DE EDUCACIÓN NACIONAL

Participant

08/2018 – Present Seedbed of Talents

Bogotá, COL FUNDACIÓN COLFUTURO

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Participant

03/2020 - 09/2021 "Ausbildung von in Deutschland lebenden

Lateinamerikanern/innen als Multiplikatoren/innen für die entwicklungspolitische Bildungsarbeit"

Modules: Water, Energy and Climate, Displacement and

Migration, and Consumption.

LATEINAMERIKA-ZENTRUM E.V.

Bonn, DEU LATEINAMERIKA-ZENTRUM E.V.

Duties Design multiple didactic resources for school children to address world's current most

pressing challenges from both German and Latin American perspectives.

Volunteer

02/2018 - 09/2019

- · Communal Work Manager
- Peace Education Program Coordinator
- Environmental Sustainability Program Member Neighborhood "los Laureles", loc. San Cristóbal

Division of Community Experience

Bogotá, COL FUNDACIÓN TECHO - COLOMBIA

Duties Design, manage and evaluate Community Developm

Design, manage and evaluate Community Development Projects. Create and implement strategies aimed to enhance abilities and capacities related to Peace and harmonious coexistence between children and teenagers living in informal settlements. Plan social intervention procedures with vulnerable population. Lead large groups of volunteers on the field. Instruct and inspire new volunteers through structured seminars. Organize,

plan and execute large-scale events.

Volunteer

04/2017 – 04/2019 Environmental Planning

Tenjo, COL ITACA: ESPACIO ECOCULTURAL

Duties Plan reforestation and environmental recovery actions on damaged over-exploited zones.

Lead groups of volunteers on the field. Instruct volunteers on how to seed, transplant and

care saplings.

Nicolas E. Fajardo-Acosta March 17, 2022